<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learnings and thoughts</title>
    <link>http://magonye.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Learnings and thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:43:44 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://magonye.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>welcome to my blog</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/welcome-to-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:43:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/welcome-to-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just created this blog for learning pourposes. I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn a lot of things. I think this blog can help me, but also some of my learnings can help someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy it as I&amp;rsquo;m going to enjoy it, and feel free to comment, suggest or  correct any of the content I will be posting here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that everything is about learning, enjoying, sharing and teaching. No matter  yours skills, the most important is the will of learn and teach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who am I? I&amp;rsquo;m Mike, a programmer that thought, some time ago, that he already knew everything that was needed to know to be a good programmer, but now, the only thing that I&amp;rsquo;m sure is that I have a long journey. A journey to learn to be a better professional. And that journey will never end!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;image left&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://magonye.github.io/img/main/magonye.png&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
Mike Gonzalez &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Software Engineer since 2000: I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bored (also boring, I guess&amp;hellip;) Java developer for many many years. I made my job, without caring my methodology or skills. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t concerned about doing my job with professionalism neither enthusiasm.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Father of two incredible kids: Adrià and Claudia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Runner and free athlete: I think we should care also our body and health, as we care our mind and skills. The mix of these two worlds, makes us better humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Learner: I&amp;rsquo;ve just realized I was at the wrong path. I&amp;rsquo;ve just change my mindset. Now I found the right path: happiness, proudness, skillness, the will to learn and share, just being inconformist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn a lot of things, and this blog will help me: I will share my new learnings, the articles or books I read, the courses I will take, the conferences I will assist&amp;hellip;.   I hope you will enjoy it, but also teach me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also can follow me here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;icons&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//github.com/magonye&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;GitHub&#34; class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//linkedin.com/in/miguel-angel-gonzalez-yepes-11898244&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;LinkedIn&#34; class=&#34;fa fa-linkedin&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//twitter.com/MikeGonYe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34; class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>