<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learnings and thoughts</title>
    <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learnings and thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 12:55:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://magonye.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>JBCNConf 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/jbcnconf2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 12:55:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/jbcnconf2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/Optimized-jbcnconf2017.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 19th, 20th and 21st of June, I assisted to JBCNConf2017 with two colleagues. For me was the second time, as I assisted to JBCNConf last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will try to explain you a little &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is JBCNConf, &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s important to assist to conferences, and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; was my experience at this conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I&amp;rsquo;m late, because I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on August and the conference was on June, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to miss the opportunity to write about JBCNConf, and payback something to the conference in return, as I learned a lot of things there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-jbcnconf&#34;&gt;What is JBCNConf?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an event organized by Barcelona JUG. This year was the third edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JUG stands for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_User_Group&#34;&gt;Java User Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several talks about Java world and related technologies, as JVM languages (like Scala, Clojure, Groovy, etc&amp;hellip;), functional programming, micro-services, Docker, TDD, etc..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some workshops, related to Java world too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year the conference was on a great venue: a multi theater building. The seats were amazing, full visibility, great screens, excellent audio, &amp;hellip; but if I had to say something negative, maybe the place for the breakfast and lunch was small, as there were a lot of people attending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshops took place at a nearby hotel, so we were very comfortable with our laptops. At the workshops, there were problems with the wifi. I think the hotel was not ready to have so many people searching for some wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization was great, they were assisting any kind of doubts and problems, and helping all the speakers. They did a really good work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-data&#34;&gt;Some data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here some data information about the numbers of the three editions (As you can see, the evolution is impressive.):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;2015&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;2016&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;2017&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 days&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 days&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 days&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 tracks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 tracks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 tracks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;41 talks &amp;amp; workshops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50 talks &amp;amp; workshops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;58 talks &amp;amp; workshops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;210 assistants&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;320 assistants&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450 assistants&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-i-should-assist&#34;&gt;Why I should assist?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons why you should assist to the JBCNConf, here are the main ones (&lt;em&gt;IMHO&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can know what&amp;rsquo;s trending topic on Java world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Known Java developers from all around the world talk about their knowledge, innovation and developments during this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to interact with others Java enthusiast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organization does a really great work: good speakers and talks, moderate price, great venue, very enthusiastic people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;opening-keynote&#34;&gt;Opening Keynote&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/venkat-subramaniam.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dr. Venkat Subramaniam&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom:.25em;width: 120px; float: right;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Opening Keynote was performed by &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Venkat Subramaniam&lt;/strong&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jbcnconf.com/2017/infoSpeaker.html?ref=venkat&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/venkat_s&#34;&gt;@venkat_s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile Developer founder, creator of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.agilelearner.com/&#34;&gt;agilelearner.com&lt;/a&gt;, and professor at the University of Houston.
Author of books, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/1937785467&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Functional Programming in Java&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/8184041896&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practices of an Agile Developer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B01M1DHQJ7&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pragmatic Scala&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-art-of-simplicity&#34;&gt;The Art of Simplicity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk was very inspirational, about the art of making things simple: as developers we are very used to do things in a complex way, because simple things are not so funny&amp;hellip; but also not so easy!!!
Can we distinguish simple things from complex ones? The search of the simplicity, as itself, is a challenge, and it requires a lot to practice, in order to be a master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the same talk &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I4wuMV8N6Iw&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, for the DevDay Conference on 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;closing-note&#34;&gt;Closing note&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/sandro-mancuso.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sandro Mancuso&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom:.25em;width: 120px; float: right;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Closing Note was performed by &lt;strong&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/strong&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jbcnconf.com/2017/infoSpeaker.html?ref=sandro&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sandromancuso&#34;&gt;@sandromancuso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software craftsman and founder at &lt;a href=&#34;http://codurance.com/&#34;&gt;Codurance&lt;/a&gt;, author of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/0134052501&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Software Craftsman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and founder of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://londonswcraft.com/&#34;&gt;London Software Craftsmanship Community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-long-road&#34;&gt;The Long Road&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very inspirational talk about developers careers. Developers must take the ownership of their own careers, and see it as a whole. If we look our career as a ladder, every job change is a single step that make us go forward .
Are we the owners of our career? Do we know where we want to go? If we look backwards, are we proud of what we have done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the same talk &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/167722761&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, for the NEWCRAFTS Conferences on 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-talks-and-workshops&#34;&gt;Other talks and workshops&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to many talks and workshops. All of them were great, but I would to talk in detail about two of them, the ones that impressed me more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;clean-lambdas&#34;&gt;Clean Lambdas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/victor-rentea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Victor Rentea&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom:.25em;width: 120px; float: right;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A talk by &lt;strong&gt;Victor Rentea&lt;/strong&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jbcnconf.com/2017/infoSpeaker.html?ref=victor-rentea&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/victorrentea&#34;&gt;@victorrentea‏&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a kind of workshop, but he did it as a talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk was amazing to me. To be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect too much, as it was the first talk, and the topic wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of my favourites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk was about java8 lambdas and streams, and how we can write them in a clean way. The usage of this java8 feature is growing, but not everybody knows how to use them well, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to have bad code with them. The talk was funny, Victor was all the time writing code to us, showing us many refactors we can apply to lambdas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some weeks after, on my team, we practiced the same workshop of Clean Lambdas, I must admit my level of knowledge about streams and lambdas increased a lot since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find Victor Rentea&amp;rsquo;s Clean Lambdas repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/victorrentea/java8-voxxed&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uH9A37k2QkU&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; a video of the same workshop, he did before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/VictorRentea/clean-lambdas-streams-in-java8&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; the slides of the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;test-refactoring&#34;&gt;Test Refactoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/wlodek.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wlodek Krakowski&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom:.25em;width: 120px; float: right;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A workshop by &lt;strong&gt;Wlodek Krakowski&lt;/strong&gt; (more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jbcnconf.com/2017/infoSpeaker.html?ref=wlodek&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wlodekkr&#34;&gt;@wlodekkr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop was about the importance to maintain your test in a good shape, and why you should do some refactoring also on your tests, not only on your production code. This may be something obvious when you hear of it, but not always you do refactoring on your test as your daily work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wlodek also talked about mastering your IDE, and knowing all the shortcuts and options your IDE gives you in order to do refactors with security and very quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to follow the workshop, but Wlodek was so fast and I was so slow, that I finally gave up the workshop, and I decided to enjoy watching Wlodek working on a huge test refactoring. It was amazing the ability of Wlodek, and how he masters tdd and refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can know more about Wlodek &lt;a href=&#34;http://refactoring.pl/en/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I will repeat next year with no doubt!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Did you assist to any conference? Do you think every developer should assist to them? Please, give me your feedback, it will be very appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Manager: Why and how to store passwords securely</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/password-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 08:26:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/password-manager/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/password-manager.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Password Manager&#34; title=&#34;Password Manager&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I&amp;rsquo;m working on a the team that needs to handle with a lot of passwords. These passwords are critical for the company, as they are mainly Payment Provider password accounts.
Since now, we were using different kind of storage mechanisms, non of them really secure (internal confluence pages, shared plain text files, etc&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in order to upgrade our security standards, we needed to choose some mechanism that could provide us the following features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure&lt;/strong&gt;: Of course this was the main goal, we wanted something really secure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborative&lt;/strong&gt;: We needed something that could be accessed from different computers, from inside the company, and outside, as we have a colleague on remote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Platform&lt;/strong&gt;: We have several computer flavours on the team (OSX - Win - Linux).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-solution&#34;&gt;The solution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some research, and also consulting our security consultants, we decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://keepass.info/&#34;&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt;. KeePass is a free open source password manager that stores passwords in an encrypted database, and locked by a master password or/and a key file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KeePass uses very secure encryption algorithms (AES and Twofish). You can find more information &lt;a href=&#34;http://keepass.info/features.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can place the encrypted password file on a company shared folder, on cloud or even on local at your machine. As much secure the place you stored it, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some security rules are recommended: the usage of strong and long master password, and defining a rotation for the master password are some of them. Our master password is 100 char length, and it rotates every 30 days. This is something that KeePass helps you, with a lot of useful options and tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of implementations of KeePass, you can found them &lt;a href=&#34;http://keepass.info/download.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As you could see, all most known platforms are covered, from computers to mobile devices.
Some of these implementations allows you to store the encrypted password file on a cloud storage, so the combinations are multiple, you need to choose the one that fits you more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-did-we-learn&#34;&gt;What did we learn?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We realized that not everybody inside the team was storing their password properly, so we installed a personal KeePass file for those, so they could stored their password safely. They improved their personal security, and the security of the team, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also realized that we can store on KeePass almost everything, not only payment provider passwords, also infrastructure passwords or important documents and files. Everything now is secured!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;which-are-the-next-steps&#34;&gt;Which are the next steps?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to create two different password files, on for test environments and another for production environments. Now we have only one file, with both environment together. With the split, we will gain security, and we will be able to give more granularity access to our environments, depending of the role of the team member. There are team members that don&amp;rsquo;t need to have access to our production environments, only to the test ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have any experience with password managers? Do you know a better way to solve this? Please, give me your feedback, it will be very appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git: how to squash commits already pushed</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/git-squash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 08:30:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/git-squash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/git-squash-photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Git Squash Main photo&#34; title=&#34;Git Squash Main photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I was working on feature in a project, and after a lot of commits and pushes, I wanted to show to my colleagues my changes&amp;hellip;. but I wanted to show them in a single commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could I join my 10 commits in a single one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had heard about squashing commits with git before, so I was confident it would be easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Googling a little, and reading some examples, I was confident about what I had to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git rebase -i HEAD~10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/docs/git-rebase#_interactive_mode&#34;&gt;git documentation&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to know more about &lt;em&gt;git rebase&lt;/em&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is the interactive mode (&lt;strong&gt;-i&lt;/strong&gt;), that allows you to edit the commits which are being rebased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the editor  opened, with the list of commits that I was rebasing, and some instructions. Something similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pick affab1e The first commit for the feature
pick accab1e The second commit for the feature
...
pick abcdef1 The last commit for the feature
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I only had to change the second and following commits, replacing &lt;em&gt;pick&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;squash&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pick affab1e The first commit for the feature
squash accab1e The second commit for the feature
...
squash abcdef1 The last commit for the feature
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking to my &lt;em&gt;git log&lt;/em&gt;, I was exulting. Now the log looked amazing, with my new brand feature in a very single commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the problems began when I tried to push the &lt;em&gt;rebased&lt;/em&gt; commit. Git didn&amp;rsquo;t allow me, because I was required to do a &lt;em&gt;git pull&lt;/em&gt; before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I got stack on an evil loop:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://magonye.github.io/img/git-squash-evilloop.png&#34; alt=&#34;Git Squash Evil Loop&#34; style=&#34;width: 400px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few attempts, and the priceless help of a colleague, I realized that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t go forward with the squash this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process would work to me if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t pushed the commits that I wanted to squash. On this scenario, Git wouldn&amp;rsquo;t ask me for a &lt;em&gt;git pull&lt;/em&gt;, and I could push my squashed commit without problems. And that is because my remote repository wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have any of the commits I was trying to squash, as my local repo would be beyond my remote repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I needed to do was to force push with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push origin +branch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this command, that worked to me as a charm, finally I was able to push my feature to the branch as a single commit, although I had already pushed it before in separated commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more info about &lt;strong&gt;+&amp;lt;refspec&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; command at the official documentation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/docs/git-push#git-push---force&#34;&gt;git push&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have any experience with squash? Do you know a better way to solve this? Please, give me your feedback, it will be very appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>july 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 09:33:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/july-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a very challenging month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started a Community of Practice at my work. It&amp;rsquo;s very exciting to share and learn things with other colleagues. We&amp;rsquo;re doing some katas and lighting talks. It&amp;rsquo;s only the beginning, but I think we can improve a lot with these meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also reading some books. I&amp;rsquo;m reading two of them (Sandro Mancuso&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;The Software Craftsman&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Growing Object Oriented Software&lt;/strong&gt;) with other people. It&amp;rsquo;s very interesting to read a book with some other people. When talking about the book, you can see another point of view about the same chapters, and ask or share thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started the Intro to TDD by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jbrains.ca/&#34;&gt;J.BRains&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read all these posts during July:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/0x13a/why-null-references-are-a-bad-idea&#34;&gt;Why null references are a bad idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.genbetadev.com/paradigmas-de-programacion/el-resurgir-de-la-programacion-funcional&#34;&gt;El resurgir de la programación funcional&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.genbetadev.com/formacion/pattern-matching&#34;&gt;Pattern matching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/suhas_chatekar/why-should-you-use-standard-http-methods-while-designing-rest-apis&#34;&gt;Why should you use standard http methods while designing rest apis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://culto.latercera.com/2017/03/15/deje-de-leer/&#34;&gt;Dejé de leer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/finding-time-to-become-a-better-developer-eebc154881b2&#34;&gt;Finding time to become a better developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/andreasklinger/comments-explain-why-not-what-and-2-more-rules-on-writing-good-comments&#34;&gt;Comments explain why not what and 2 more rules on writing good comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/raulavila/my-experience-with-pair-programming&#34;&gt;My experience with pair programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.takipi.com/5-step-recipe-everything-you-need-to-know-for-staying-up-to-date-in-java/&#34;&gt;5 step recipe everything you need to know for staying up to date in java&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/pbeekums/you-cant-learn-everything&#34;&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t learn everything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/storage/assets/5776001-dzone-rc241-declarativepipelinewithjenkins.pdf&#34;&gt;Declarative pipeline with Jenkins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/notes/kent-beck/mastering-programming/1184427814923414&#34;&gt;Mastering programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/ben/my-three-tips-for-maintaining-fitness-and-a-healthy-lifestyle-as-a-software-developer&#34;&gt;My three tips for maintaining fitness and a healthy lifestyle as a software developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/scalawilliam/unit-testing-is-simple&#34;&gt;Unit testing is simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/binarforge/seven-useful-programming-habits&#34;&gt;Seven useful programming habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/gazebo_c/making-and-taking-babysteps&#34;&gt;Making and taking babysteps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/samjarman/how-to-get-started-with-public-speaking&#34;&gt;How to get started with public speaking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.samjarman.co.nz/blog/code-reviews&#34;&gt;Code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/hitman666/git-branching-done-right-with-gitflow--improving-code-quality-with-code-reviews&#34;&gt;Git branching done right with gitflow: improving code quality with code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/pbeekums/the-problem-with-heroes-in-software-development&#34;&gt;The problem with heroes in software development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/mohamed3on/brief-introduction-to-salts-in-hashing&#34;&gt;Brief introduction to salts in hashing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/jmourtada/a-quick-introduction-to-git&#34;&gt;A quick introduction to git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mike_acton/12-tips-for-making-the-best-use-of-your-time-909be33398b4&#34;&gt;12 tips for making the best use of your time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://langui.sh/2010/11/14/pbpaste-pbcopy-in-mac-os-x-or-terminal-clipboard-fun/&#34;&gt;pbpaste-pbcopy in mac os x or terminal clipboard fun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/bormod/how-to-choose-an-open-source-project-to-contribute-to&#34;&gt;How to choose an open source project to contribute to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2017/07/11/PragmaticFunctionalProgramming.html&#34;&gt;Pragmatic Functional Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/gonedark/you-changed-the-code-you-didnt-refactor-the-code&#34;&gt;You changed the code, you didn&amp;rsquo;t refactor the code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/samjarman/how-to-supercharge-your-learning-of-new-technologies&#34;&gt;How to supercharge your learning of new technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/schreiber_chris/the-benefits-of-having-a-craftsman-in-your-team&#34;&gt;The benefits of having a craftsman in your team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/optional-anti-patterns&#34;&gt;Optional: anti-patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/nishparadox/builder-design-pattern&#34;&gt;Builder design pattern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.agustinperalt.es/volver-estudiar/&#34;&gt;Volver a estudiar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/my-journey-towards-software-craftsmanship-3efdd53ac9fb&#34;&gt;My journey towards software craftsmanship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/maurobringolf/open-source-9-steps-to-my-first-feature-contribution-in-babel&#34;&gt;Open source: 9 steps to my first feature contribution in Babel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetprocess.com/articles/speed-in-software-development/&#34;&gt;Speed in software development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/tamrrat/blogging-driven-learning&#34;&gt;Blogging driven learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/gonedark/git---command-line-vs-guis&#34;&gt;Git: command line vs guis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/jackmarchant/no-excuses-write-unit-tests&#34;&gt;No excuses write unit tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>june 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 20:43:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/june-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month has been a very productive one. Actually I&amp;rsquo;m reading three books at a time: &lt;strong&gt;Clean Code&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;em&gt;Uncle Bob&lt;/em&gt;], &lt;strong&gt;Test Driven Development by Example&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;em&gt;Kent Beck&lt;/em&gt;] and &lt;strong&gt;The Software Craftsman&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;em&gt;Sandro Mancuso&lt;/em&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the books, I&amp;rsquo;ve read the following links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/130256611&#34;&gt;INTERACTION DRIVEN DESIGN - Sandro Mancuso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dDofYAOkpts&#34;&gt;Introduction to DDD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wecodesignpodcast.com/2017/06/06/toma-de-requisitos/&#34;&gt;Toma-de-requisitos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.linkedin.com/distributed-systems/log-what-every-software-engineer-should-know-about-real-time-datas-unifying&#34;&gt;Logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.koalite.com/2017/05/evitar-la-deuda-tecnica-es-un-error/&#34;&gt;Technical debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://programar.cloud/post/demo-del-api-gateway-kong/&#34;&gt;Security on APIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ronjeffries.com/xprog/articles/refactoring-not-on-the-backlog/&#34;&gt;Ron Jeffries&amp;rsquo; Refactoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/nishparadox/builder-design-pattern&#34;&gt;Builder design pattern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://codurance.com/2017/06/13/how-do-I-convince/&#34;&gt;Sandro Mancuso&amp;rsquo;s Codurance Blog - How do I convince&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 22 of Growing Object-Oriented Software (Goos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/ericgu/2017/06/22/notdd/&#34;&gt;NoTDD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>may 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 01:06:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/may-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month has been a very quiet month. No much reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/aprendiendo-a-aprender/home/welcome&#34;&gt;Learning how to learn&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; course at Coursera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also finished a very interesting course at Udemy: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/how-to-become-a-better-developer/&#34;&gt;How to become a better developer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would recommend both courses to everybody. They are clear, very well explained, and the topics are very helpfull. If you want to be a better developer and you have a lot of things to learn, you may consider to take these courses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>april 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 18:07:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/april-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My current read book is Clean Code, by Robert C. Martin. This is a MUST book, and it&amp;rsquo;s some kind embarrassing I didn&amp;rsquo;t read it before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also attending the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/aprendiendo-a-aprender/home/welcome&#34;&gt;Learning how to learn&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; course at Coursera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the book, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to fix my fault, and with the course I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pave the road. If I want to learn a lot of things, I need to know how to become efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all my readings in this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://12factor.net/&#34;&gt;The Twelve Factor Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.docker.com/introduction-to-docker&#34;&gt;Introduction to Docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.docker.com/docker-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Docker fundamentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.docker.com/docker-operations&#34;&gt;Docker Operations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rogerdudler.github.io/git-guide/&#34;&gt;Simple Git command guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KsVWdGOnHZU&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA Tips and Tricks Part I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EvXpgL2iho4&#34;&gt;IntelliJ IDEA Tips and Tricks Part II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://codurance.com/2015/03/16/installing-zprezto-a-quick-guide/&#34;&gt;How to install Prezto with zsh for your OS X terminal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2014/03/27/spotify-engineering-culture-part-1/&#34;&gt;Spotify Engineering Culture Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2014/09/20/spotify-engineering-culture-part-2/&#34;&gt;Spotify Engineering Culture Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>welcome to my blog</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/welcome-to-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:43:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/welcome-to-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just created this blog for learning pourposes. I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn a lot of things. I think this blog can help me, but also some of my learnings can help someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy it as I&amp;rsquo;m going to enjoy it, and feel free to comment, suggest or  correct any of the content I will be posting here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that everything is about learning, enjoying, sharing and teaching. No matter  yours skills, the most important is the will of learn and teach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who am I? I&amp;rsquo;m Mike, a programmer that thought, some time ago, that he already knew everything that was needed to know to be a good programmer, but now, the only thing that I&amp;rsquo;m sure is that I have a long journey. A journey to learn to be a better professional. And that journey will never end!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>