<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>monthly on Learnings and thoughts</title>
    <link>http://magonye.github.io/categories/monthly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in monthly on Learnings and thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 16:56:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://magonye.github.io/categories/monthly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>march 2018</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 16:56:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/march-2018/</guid>
      <description>This month I finished the book Extreme Programming Explained. And I&amp;rsquo;m starting reading the book The Pragmatic Programmer.
I read all these post and watched these videos during this month:
 Back To The Basics by Jason Gorman Introduction to IDD by Sandro Mancuso Growing your career by Nacho Duplication, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome by Rachel M. Carmena XP Simplicity Rules Kent Beck Design Rules Programming like Kent Beck The last responsible moment Should code have an expiry date?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>february 2018</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/february-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 11:34:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/february-2018/</guid>
      <description>This month I read the book Understanding the Four Rules of Simple Design.
I read all these post and watched these videos during this month:
 Who is Jordan Peterson? Dr. Jordan Peterson&amp;rsquo;s 10 step guide to clearer thinking through essay writing The 12 Factor App: a java developers perspective 12 Factor App in plain english El manifiesto the Twelve Factor App 12 Factor App What does three question marks in scala mean Continuous Delivery: Germinando una cultura Agile moderna - by Edu Ferro Practical Test Pyramid by Martin Fowler Software as a Craft by Rachel M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>january 2018</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/january-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 08:24:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/january-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started two new books: Functional Programming, Simplified: (Scala edition) and Extreme Programming Explained: Embrace Change (The XP Series).
I read all these post and watched these videos during this month:
 Microservices Architecture for eCommerce Valores y principios en el diseño del software - Fran Reyes #CAS2017 Kotlin for Java Programmers by Venkat Subramaniam  
Always learning!! Always improving!! Always sharing!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>december 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 08:13:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/december-2017/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m actualy doing the Coursera course &amp;ldquo;Functional Programming Principles in Scala&amp;rdquo; by École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne. This course is part of the Functional Programming in Scala Specialization. This course is taught by Martin Odersky, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to discover functional programming in Scala. I recommend it!
I read all these post and watched these videos during this month:
 Joan Tolos: Social Networking kata Sandro Mancuso: IDD Pragmatically storing security sensitive data using AWS KMS How to help protect sensitive data with AWS KMS Codemotion 2017: Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>november 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 08:10:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/november-2017/</guid>
      <description>I read all these post and watched these videos during this month:
 LSCConf 2017 Nat Pryce LSCConf 2017 Alex Bolboaca 4 Rules for Simple Design XP Simplicity Rules Adi Bolboaca: TDD as if you meant it 1 Adi Bolboaca: TDD as if you meant it 2 Adi Bolboaca: TDD as if you meant it 3 Adi Bolboaca: TDD as if you meant it 4 Adi Bolboaca: TDD as if you meant it 5 Adi Bolboaca: TDD as if you meant it 6 Adi Bolboaca: TDD as if you meant it 7</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>october 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 08:05:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/october-2017/</guid>
      <description>This month I started a new book: The Mythical Man-Month, within a Book Club.
I also stated watching the vide episodes by Adrian Balboaca about TDD as if you meant it.
Finally, I also added videos to my conferences videos, so, please, watch them and enjoy them as much as I did. You can find them here.
I read all these post and watched these videos during this month:
 docker health check instruction why isn’t agile working SOLID by yegor stop aliasing core git commands Knowing what is there entendiendo la nube: el significado de saas, paas y iaas How products got their names Lambda World Conference Crafting better code reviews Craft thinking  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>september 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 08:29:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/september-2017/</guid>
      <description>I finished The Software Craftsman: Professionalism, Pragmatism, Pride by Sandro Mancuso. It&amp;rsquo;s an incredible book, very inspirational and plenty of good advices. I will review and publish it soon.
I read all these post and watched these videos during this month:
 do we have a good safety net to change this legacy code its not just someone else&amp;rsquo;s computer what is blockchain 6 tools to boost your development workflow como gestionar tu blog con trello how disobedience made me better heres what you can learn in 10 minutes that will be useful for the rest of your programming career docker swarm tutorial Start using Java 9 shell jshell with docker java se support for docker cpu and memory limits java inside docker jshell tutorial the insecure developer mvc delievery mechanism dm  life at codurance by robert firek Mars Rover kata by Sandro Mancuso</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>august 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 15:12:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/august-2017/</guid>
      <description>This month I did the following things:
 Book Club: Actually reading The Software Craftsman by Sandro Mancuso, and NonViolent Comunication by Marshall B. Rosenberg. Typing training: I started doing some typing training at typing.com. There are other options, like typingstudy.com, typingclub.com or cursomeca.com. I&amp;rsquo;ll try them soon. Software design patterns: I started reviewing software design patterns at sourcemaking.com. This is something I need to improve, in order to know and understand them better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>july 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 09:33:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/july-2017/</guid>
      <description>It was a very challenging month!
We started a Community of Practice at my work. It&amp;rsquo;s very exciting to share and learn things with other colleagues. We&amp;rsquo;re doing some katas and lighting talks. It&amp;rsquo;s only the beginning, but I think we can improve a lot with these meetings.
I&amp;rsquo;m also reading some books. I&amp;rsquo;m reading two of them (Sandro Mancuso&amp;rsquo;s The Software Craftsman and Growing Object Oriented Software) with other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>june 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 20:43:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/june-2017/</guid>
      <description>This month has been a very productive one. Actually I&amp;rsquo;m reading three books at a time: Clean Code [Uncle Bob], Test Driven Development by Example [Kent Beck] and The Software Craftsman [Sandro Mancuso].
Besides the books, I&amp;rsquo;ve read the following links:
 INTERACTION DRIVEN DESIGN - Sandro Mancuso Introduction to DDD Toma-de-requisitos Logs Technical debt Security on APIs Ron Jeffries&#39; Refactoring Builder design pattern Sandro Mancuso&amp;rsquo;s Codurance Blog - How do I convince&amp;hellip; Chapter 22 of Growing Object-Oriented Software (Goos) NoTDD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>may 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 01:06:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/may-2017/</guid>
      <description>This month has been a very quiet month. No much reading.
I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished the &amp;ldquo;Learning how to learn&amp;rdquo; course at Coursera.
I also finished a very interesting course at Udemy: &amp;ldquo;How to become a better developer&amp;rdquo;.
I would recommend both courses to everybody. They are clear, very well explained, and the topics are very helpfull. If you want to be a better developer and you have a lot of things to learn, you may consider to take these courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>april 2017</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 18:07:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/april-2017/</guid>
      <description>My current read book is Clean Code, by Robert C. Martin. This is a MUST book, and it&amp;rsquo;s some kind embarrassing I didn&amp;rsquo;t read it before.
I&amp;rsquo;m also attending the &amp;ldquo;Learning how to learn&amp;rdquo; course at Coursera.
With the book, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to fix my fault, and with the course I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pave the road. If I want to learn a lot of things, I need to know how to become efficient.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
