<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>culture-of-learning on Learnings and thoughts</title>
    <link>http://magonye.github.io/categories/culture-of-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in culture-of-learning on Learnings and thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 08:37:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://magonye.github.io/categories/culture-of-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Habits</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/building-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 08:37:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/building-habits/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that it&amp;rsquo;s very tough for many people is to build habits that last in time, and become part of our life. Everyone probably knows what they should be doing, but they aren&amp;rsquo;t. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be anything tech-related, it could be also some lifestyle activity, such as reading or practicing any kind of sport.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also found it&amp;rsquo;s very hard to maintain habits through time, so I&amp;rsquo;ll share with you the things that are working for me, and maybe you could also adopt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD Pipeline Kata</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/jenkins-kata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 08:08:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/jenkins-kata/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago other team was managing the pipeline of my team&amp;rsquo;s applications, and they were also testing and deploying our applications.
This separation of responsibility between creating the software and making it run was leading us to:
 No ownership of the deployment process: feeling of non responsibility within the team. Errors on environments: No visibility of where our code was being deployed was producing sometimes problems with configuration on environments, and they were tough to fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture Of Learning: Book Club</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/cultureoflearning-bookclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 08:21:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/cultureoflearning-bookclub/</guid>
      <description>Reading books is one of the activities everyone who is interested in software should do. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to learn new things, new points of view, new theories or practices. There are several books that every developer should read. But sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to get time to read it, you aren&amp;rsquo;t motivated enough, or even if you are reading the book, the book is hard to understand.
By reading a book in a Book Club, you will discover a new way of learning from a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture Of Learning: Lunch and Learn</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/cultureoflearning-lunchandlearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 08:29:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/cultureoflearning-lunchandlearn/</guid>
      <description>During this year we are experiencing a very huge transformation as a team. We are living an interesting journey to become a more mature team, an autonomous team inside the company. And this transformation includes a lot of practices and activities. With this series of posts, that I&amp;rsquo;ll call Culture of Learning, I will try to explain in detail each of these activities, how we started them, how we do them and what they give us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>