<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about-me on Learnings and thoughts</title>
    <link>http://magonye.github.io/categories/about-me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about-me on Learnings and thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://magonye.github.io/categories/about-me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CURRICULUM VITAE</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Miguel Angel Gonzalez Yepes Software Engineer         SUMMARY Software Engineer with more than 20 years of experience building web-based applications in several sectors: tourism, pharmaceutical/hospital, retail &amp;amp; e-commerce and finance.
In constant evolution, I never stop learning and questioning myself as a professional.
A practitioner of agile methodologies and XP.
 EXPERIENCE  ZOPA, Software Engineer June 2018-Present
Working in an autonomous cross-functional team using Agile methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Step</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/post/another-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 08:37:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/post/another-step/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working almost for 6 years at the same employer. It’s been the longest period in my professional career. When you are trying to get features to production quickly within a team, and at the same time learning new things and trying to refactor and improve your architecture, most of the time you don’t realize about how fast time happens.
But then, something happens. Maybe it is a teammate that leave the team (you know who you are, don’t you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://magonye.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://magonye.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Mike Gonzalez Software Engineer since 2000: I&#39;ve been a bored (also boring, I guess...) Java developer for many many years. I made my job, without caring my methodology or skills. I wasn&#39;t concerned about doing my job with professionalism neither enthusiasm.
Father of two incredible kids: Adrià and Claudia.
Runner and free athlete: I think we should care also our body and health, as we care our mind and skills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>